# GALINA KOZYREVA

Software Engineer

· +49-152-26410265

@ galinka@me.com

9 Dresden

@ www.linkedin.com/in/galina-kozyreva

## SUMMARY

I'm Galina, a software engineer with over ten years of experience in developing and maintaining various software solutions. My main skills include TypeScript, JavaScript and Python, as well as working with databases and scalable architectures. I'm currently exploring Rust and am committed to incorporating environmental sustainability into my work. With a strong willingness to learn new approaches and technologies, I love solving problems and constantly aim to improve my technical skills and teamwork to create smart, sustainable solutions

# **EDUCATION**

# Diploma in Computer Science

Saint Petersburg State University of Aerospace and Instrumentation, Faculty of Aerospace Computer and **Software Systems** 

GPA 1.9 / 1.0

iii 2010 - 2015 ♥ Saint Petersburg, Russia

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Team Lead / Senior Full stack Developer

Flowplace GmbH

苗 2022 - Present

Company Description

- Optimized the frontend UI to improve UX/UI, resulting in increased user engagement.
- Led the development of the Flowplace platform, working with TypeScript, Vue.js, Nest.js, PostgreSQL, and Prisma.
- Developed an MVP for new features to gather valuable customer feedback for product enhancements.
- Improved the CI/CD pipeline using Terraform, GitHub Actions, and DigitalOcean, resolving concurrency issues and enhancing the deployment proces.
- Ensured GDPR compliance and fortified IT security throughout the software architecture.

#### Research Associate

TU Dresden, cfaed - Center for Advancing Electronics Dresden

iiii 2021 - 2022 ♀ Dresden

Company Description

Conducted research on MLIR progressive lowering and advanced optimizations for parallel and emerging computing systems, with a focus on C++.

## Senior Software Engineer

Solactive Technologies GmbH

苗 2020 - 2021 Dresden

Company Description

- Developed a data scraping and processing service for government bonds using Python.
- Enhanced project architecture with a microservice approach and successfully transitioned it to Kubernetes.
- Established system monitoring and error notifications for robust operations.
- Contributed to frontend development using atomic design principles and React.js.

## SKILLS

Client-Side

**TypeScript** React Redux

Vue **Tailwind** Canvas Next.is

**Bootstrap** 

Server-side

Python NumPv Pandas Nest.js Node.js **PostgreSQL** Redis **AWS** Spark HTTP/2

Development & Operations

**JUnit PyUnit** Cypress

Selenium Scrum Agile GIT

# CERTIFICATION

Software Security

University of Maryland College Park, 2017

**Usable Security** 

University of Maryland College Park, 2016

Introduction to Cybersecurity Tools & Cyber Attacks

IBM, 2022

**Network Security & Database Vulnerabilities** 

IBM, 2022

# **LANGUAGES**

| English | Proficient   |
|---------|--------------|
| German  | Intermediate |
|         | Native       |

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer

Silicon Valley Insight

iiii 2018 - 2020 ♀ remote

Company Description

- Led diverse web and mobile application projects utilizing a wide range of technologies including Python, Flask, React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Next.js, and React Native.
- Managed backend projects and implemented robust software architecture solutions to optimize React Native applications.
- Conducted code reviews and mentored junior developers to enhance code quality and adherence to best practices.

# IT Security Engineer

State Research Institute of Aviation Systems

Company Description

- Defined, implemented and maintained corporate security policies.
- Analysed and advised on new security technologies and program conformance.
- · Configured and setup software and workstations.
- · Supported and trained end-users.

# **Backend Developer**

Tunnll

iii 2016 - 2017 ♀ remote

Company Description

- Developed web applications for finding buses and buying tickets in small cities in Spain.
- Used programming capabilities in Python, Flask, Angular, PostgreSQL, Heroku and Docker.
- Conducted unit testing to deliver optimal browser functionality.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.

## Python / OpenERP Developer

Scientific and Technical Centre Atlas

iii 2012 - 2014 ♥ Moscow

Company Description

- Maintained the OpenERP framework and its existing modules
- Developed new modules to automate the creation of financial documents according to Russian standards
- · Wrote specifications and documantation sutable for gouverment level.
- Tested web application using Selenium

## Freelance Developer

Freelancer

iii 2014 - 2020 ♀ remote

Company Description

- · Worked concurrently on several projects
- Worked with users within business community and IT project team members to develop applications
- Dynamic sites executed by PHP, Python and JavaScript.
- · Worked as DevOps with Ansible and Jenkins.

# IT/Business Analyst

Scientific and Technical Centre Atlas

iii 2011 - 2012 ♥ Moscow

Company Description

- · Performed business process, analysis, design and improvement activities.
- Created and maintained metrics required by business processes.
- Created UML diagrams, such as Use Case, Activity, Class and Sequence diagrams.
- Participated in test planning, preparation, execution, issue resolution and logging to ensure that all aspects of the project are in accordance with business requirements.